hi I'm an Eric Weinstein and welcome
back to my youtube video channel today
I'm sitting here with a special guest
you may know him from my Twitter feed
because I introduced him in 2009 under
the pseudonym for y ou but he's now 13
years old and I wanted the world to meet
my sons my site so thanks for coming
thanks for having me so I'm not sure
what we could best discuss but one thing
that's exciting to me is that I've
understood that you're thinking about
starting a YouTube channel can you tell
me what's going into that thought
apprentice
well I think one sort of problem with
our generations I think is bound to be a
very important generation is that at the
current age of most of our members were
not particularly verbal or expressive
and I think that this is an issue and if
maybe some past generations could sort
of get a better understanding of sort of
the the newcomers I think that could be
very very helpful to the world and I
think there's a lot that needs to be
discussed and talked about and I hope to
sort of have an outlet to share my
thoughts and ideas with the world so
that someone is our in our generation is
being expressive of what we're going
through so it's super interesting let's
rip off of that for a second I think
what I feel is that I'm learning a
tremendous amount from you because
you're not shy about expressing not only
your ideas but conflicts between the
ideas as you sort of sort of assemble a
perspective why do you suppose it is
that there's so much interest in what
people believe after the Millennials
well I think one thing which is being
becoming increasingly more and more
obvious is that this is a very very
unique time period and I think this is
going to be a very very unique
generation and I think for the most part
the world is not stable at the moment
right I think we're in sort of a
poorly defined revolution may be sort of
similar to the late 60s in the sense or
you know there's certain time periods
where no one's quite sure what to make
of the world and I think that's
definitely what we're experiencing at
the moment can I just ask you a question
with it yeah so as you know these are
your developmental years and if I just
take what you're saying about the late
60s it's probably the case that if you
were growing up and you were 13 in 1968
your brain was learning about a set of
circumstances that really were very
temporary and impertinent and permanent
do you feel that in some ways this is a
disadvantageous type to be growing up
because so much appears to be highly
unstable or do you instead have a sense
of being energized by the instability
well I think sort of my more general
take right is it's nearly impossible to
predict any of this because you know if
you think for example about technology
and how rapidly it's evolving there's
absolutely no way to predict it and to
predict what the future is going to look
like and that's something which does
seem to be sort of a definitional part
of this generation and this time period
and I think as a result of that it's
very hard to predict sort of how the
figures of our generation will will turn
out and how some of this stuff could
benefit us or become a disadvantage and
I think there's just sort of a lack of
understanding you know on the on the one
hand we're growing up with access to a
lot of stuff and I think a lot of things
are changing for the better but I think
the world is very very divided at least
in America at the moment what are you
seeing as being the major fault lines in
that division well I think to a very
large extent the right has gotten a lot
crazier and the left has gotten a lot
crazier and everyone's being forced to
pick a side so this is something which
I'm pretty unhappy about and I get the
sense that you are too and and I don't
think either side really knows what it's
doing and we're being forced to
to pick one and I think that that's
really dividing us at the moment you
know I think for example you know a lot
of people are getting categorized and
associated with alright as sort of a
boogeyman and you see sort of parallels
of this where people will be associated
with very far left figures and I think I
have a lot more experience with with one
side of this given that I've grown up in
in California in New York which are
maybe some of the the two most
democratic states in the United States
so I think you know I only have sort of
have one set of experiences but I think
it's not hard to understand what it
might be like on that on the other side
yeah I mean one of my concerns of course
is that we've never had a situation like
the Trump administration in so many
different ways and that if this is what
you think of as one of your earlier
earliest conscious political experiences
I do wonder what the kind of permanent
effect is I don't think a lot of adults
thought about what it would be like to
have a world in which we don't even seem
to agree whether the president was
democratically elected because of the
allegations of Russian vote tampering
whether people view various behaviors
but the president is so unbecoming as to
make him unfit for office or whether
other people see him is the only person
capable of running the gauntlet and
standing up for reasonable national
interests that have been demonized as if
they were jingoistic out-of-control
ultra-nationalism so that's a very I
mean even for me that's pretty confusing
Mike one of my questions would be does
your study of the past give you more
perspective on this Wow
I think to an extent but it's very very
hard to try to compare and match our
generation to anything
you know previous I think you know one
thing one example I gave which was late
60s which I think is similar but a lot
of the ways in which the world changed
were sort of dissimilar so I remember
you know when I was younger I've the
memory of mom telling me you know I'm so
happy you weren't growing up when when
some of the really nasty stuff was
coming out about Bill Clinton I have
absolutely no idea you know how I would
have dealt with with news and parenting
a child you know during that presidency
and I sort of accepted it and then you
know a few years later here we are and
it's a you know one thing I think I'm
old enough to sort of try to make sense
of this as well as you know anyone else
but it's it's very it's it's very
difficult and I think one of the really
positive things which is eventually
going to be seen more positively even
though it's causing maybe a lot of
distress at the moment is that with
however crazy things are at least people
are talking about the issues it's true
which we're sort of you know hidden
until recent years and I think that's
that will be an advantage for our
generation because there's nothing too
taboo or far-fetched to be discussed and
I think we're going to get sort of a
very complex understanding of the world
and a lot is going to be sort of
uncovered for us so I think that's sort
of one of the famines that we've
received growing up in this really
really confusing era so that at least
things are under discussion right do you
have any sense of whether you're turning
to the past or to the present for the
thinker's that mean the most you were
some of the some of the voices in the
political sphere that matter the most to
you well I think because I've grown up
in a household with you and you've been
a very very sort of strong presence and
my understanding of the world I don't
think my views are exactly the same as
as yours I know there are places we
disagree but I thank you and your
network
have have played sort of in a very
impactful role and in how I viewed the
world and I think sort of the same for
Mom and I think I don't know I don't
think anyone's politics and our family
is exactly the same so it's good because
I've gotten that sort of a spectrum even
in my own home
well I think that your mom you're
referring to Pia Milani at the Institute
for new economic thinking is one of the
most sophisticated voices that really is
connected to I would say the most
responsible version of the analytic left
from yesteryear and I think that where I
how do you see where I contribute
differently Wow I think she is as you
would sort of if you sort of seated a
very traditional leftist right and I see
you as sort of being a little bit more
of a renegade and you're trying to pick
your own path right and I think I think
my mother has played a lot of stability
and some of my political views but I
think their views which I'm I'm sort of
choosing not to hold many of them
anymore
because I feel like some of the people
that hold them now have gone so well
this is across the line
this is this this is this frustration
that both you and I have that you want
to sign up for something that seems 80%
reasonable but that there's 20 percent I
wouldn't call it 8020 what would you
call it now I don't know I think making
up statistics is always hard I can't
give you numbers but I really feel like
the world has done a lot crazier than
that and I think you know especially
with a lot of the people I've grown up
with as as part of my generation and
where I've grown up with it's it's so
far in one direction yeah that it's very
hard to try to have nuanced
conversations with people
and and I and I think that's been really
that's been really difficult you know on
one hand a lot of people are talking
about a lot of things but then within
sort of a network and an environment
there's just there's no room for for
discussion between the two teams and I
think that that's been really hard
because everything is so polish so this
is really interesting so in essence
rather than left versus right you would
prefer a nuanced group in a none turn on
nuanced group and you would feel I
assume that you see yourself as being
more to the left than the writers that
presumptuous probably and once again I
think a lot of these things are still
very flexible in me so I'm trying not to
call myself either left or right but I
don't mind looking at it on a spectrum
what look I tried for a while enough to
use the spectrum but the language just
became almost a necessity given that we
have two parties and people get very
confined I think that's unintentional I
think in many ways the media is trying
to starve us for a vocabulary which will
really allow us to talk about these
things in an attempt for different
outlets to sort of preserve their own
rhetoric
and I think it's not it's not a mistake
that there's no real language to discuss
sort of a center of the spectrum so what
can we hope for in terms of some of the
color that everybody's looking for on
what might be termed Generation Z you
need you mean my EQ panel or the
generation that follows Gen Y the
followed Gen X yeah yeah so to clarify
or thinking of starting a YouTube
channel title of generations a one
because my name is Zev and I thought
that that was that was really a hook but
also because that's probably one of the
things I'll be discussing which is
Generation Z as its titled which is what
followed the Millennials so you know I'd
like to try to get that out there I
don't mean to plug too much on your on
your video show but
subscribe now to generation Z yeah are
you doing that button active won't be
the first time you've manipulated be
effectively now do you have any closing
thoughts about what is like to follow
the Millennials and what you see the
principle differences between
generations and the Millennials as being
well I mean I think it's it's very
unclear still but you know I think
Millennials are holding increasingly
more power over the world because
they're sort of the closest to
understanding our generation so if you
look at you know the people that create
various social media networks I know you
know for example but I forget names but
I know the CEOs of snapchat for example
are like very young Millennials and I
think that's because they sort of have
an understanding of our generation and I
think that's a it's important you mean
so they both have an understanding of
the time but also they are better able
to market to that which is coming up
which is your group right and I still
don't think that they for perfect
understanding and hopefully I can try to
shed some light but looking forward to
that
yeah I will say that I've learned a ton
from you about this generation that
everybody else is curious about and so
it will be very interesting right I
would like to think for many people to
have somebody trying to speak about your
generation but in ways that can be heard
by generations that are a little older
so I'm looking forward to seeing what
you come up with let me know if I can
help in any way thanks for having me on
your show well thanks for coming be well